https://abbotslangleyclinic.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Skip to contentHomeAbout UsTour The ClinicMeet The TeamEdward BuckwaldKim JohnsonValerie ChevalierBethan JonesPrit SidhuGarry GrantHelen JonesLayla ClarkTreatmentsOrthoticsCustom Made OrthoticsTypes Of Orthotics AvailableHow We Make Your OrthoticsFoot, Leg and Heel Pain12 Benefits Of Wearing Custom Made OrthoticsWhat Conditions Can Be Helped?PricingGuaranteeTestimonialsOsteopathyChiropody & PodiatryWhat Is Chiropody?What are Verrucas and Warts?Corns and CallusesIngrown ToenailsDiabetic Foot CareChiropody PedicuresFeesCranial Osteopathy & Your ChildPhysiotherapyFoot and Gait AnalysisSports & Remedial MassageAcupunctureReflexologySports InjuriesShopContact UsOur Opening HoursAppointments & FeesContact FormFAQsHome/Privacy PolicyScopeThis document refers to personal data, which is defined as information concerning any living person (a natural person who hereafter will be called the Data Subject) that is not already in the public domain.The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which is EU wide and far more extensive than its predecessor the Data Protection Act, along with the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR), seek to protect and enhance the rights of EU data subjects. These rights cover the safeguarding of personal data, protection against the unlawful processing of personal data and the unrestricted movement of personal data within the EU and its storage within the EEA.1 - The Abbots Langley Clinic, based at 10 Abbots Rd, Abbots Langley WD5 0AZ, which hereafter for the purposes of this Privacy Notice will be referred to as The Abbots Langley Clinic, is pleased to provide the following information:2 - Who we are The Abbots Langley Clinic diagnose and treat health conditions. Treatments are carried out in accordance with the Institute of Osteopathy’s patient charter http://www.iosteopathy.org/osteopathy/the-patient-charter/. The Abbots Langley Clinic may also provide other treatments, about which our staff will be pleased to provide more details. These include Physiotherapy, Podiatry & Chiropody, Orthotics, Sports Massage and Acupuncture.3 - Personal Data a) For the purposes of providing treatment, The Abbots Langley Clinic may require detailed medical information. We will only collect what is relevant and necessary for your treatment. When you visit our clinic, we will make notes which may include details concerning your medication, treatment and other issues affecting your health. This data is always held securely, is not shared with anyone not involved in your treatment, although for data storage purposes it may be handled by pre-vetted staff who have all signed an integrity and confidentiality agreement. To be able to process your personal data it is a condition of any treatment that you give your explicit consent to allow The Abbots Langley Clinic to document and process your personal medical data. Contact details provided by you such as telephone numbers, email addresses, postal addresses may be used to remind you of future appointments and provide reports or other information concerning your treatment.
b) Some basic personal data may be collected about you from the marketing forms and surveys you complete, from records of our correspondence and phone calls and details of your visits to our website, including but not limited to, personally identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.
c) The Abbots Langley Clinic’ website uses cookies, which is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. WordPress.org uses cookies to help The Abbots Langley Clinic to identify and track visitors and their website access preferences. The Abbots Langley Clinic’ website visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using The Abbots Langley Clinic’ website. d) The Abbots Langley Clinic will only collect the information needed so that we can provide you with the services you require, the business does not sell or broker your data.4 - Legal basis for processing any personal data To meet our contractual obligations obtained from explicit Patient Consent and legitimate interest to respond to enquiries concerning the services provided.5 - Legitimate interests pursued by The Abbots Langley Clinic To promote treatments for patients with all types of health problems indicated for osteopathic care.6 – Consent Through agreeing to this privacy notice you are consenting to The Abbots Langley Clinic processing your personal data for the purposes outlined. You can withdraw consent at any time by using the postal, email address or telephone number provided at the end of this Privacy Notice.7 – Disclosure The Abbots Langley Clinic will keep your personal information safe and secure, only staff engaged in providing your treatment will have access to your patient records, although our administration team will have access to your contact details so that they can make appointments and manage your account. The Abbots Langley Clinic will not disclose your Personal Information unless compelled to, in order to meet legal obligations, regulations or valid governmental requests. The clinic may also enforce its Terms and Conditions, including investigating potential violations of its Terms and Conditions to detect, prevent or mitigate fraud or security or technical issues; or to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of its staff.8 - Retention Policy The Abbots Langley Clinic will process personal data during the duration of any treatment and will continue to store only the personal data needed for eight years after the contract has expired to meet any legal obligations. After eight years all personal data will be deleted, unless basic information needs to be retained by us to meet our future obligations to you, such as erasure details. Records concerning minors who have received treatment will be retained until the child has reached the age of 25.9 - Data storage All Data is held in the United Kingdom. The Abbots Langley Clinic does not store personal data outside the EEA.10 - Your rights as a data subject At any point whilst The Abbots Langley Clinic are in possession of, or processing your personal data, all data subjects have the following rights:Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you.Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you have a right to restrict the processing.Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the right not to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling.In the event that The Abbots Langley Clinic refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why, which you have the right to legally challenge. At your request The Abbots Langley Clinic can confirm what information it holds about you and how it is processed.11 - You can request the following information:Identity and the contact details of the person or organisation (The Abbots Langley Clinic) that has determined how and why to process your data.Contact details of the GDPR Co-Ordinator, where applicable.The purpose of the processing as well as the legal basis for processing.If the processing is based on the legitimate interests of The Abbots Langley Clinic and information about these interests.The categories of personal data collected, stored and processed.Recipient(s) or categories of recipients that the data is/will be disclosed to.How long the data will be stored.Details of your rights to correct, erasure, restrict or object to such processing.Information about your right to withdraw consent at any time.How to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority (ICO).Whether the provision of personal data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract, as well as whether you are obliged to provide the personal data and the possible consequences of failing to provide such data.The source of personal data if it wasn’t collected directly from you.Any details and information of automated decision making, such as profiling, and any meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and expected consequences of such processing.12 - To access what personal data is held, identification will be required The Abbots Langley Clinic will accept the following forms of identification (ID) when information on your personal data is requested: a copy of your driving licence, passport, birth certificate and a utility bill not older than three months. A minimum of one piece of photographic ID listed above and a supporting document is required. If The Abbots Langley Clinic is dissatisfied with the quality, further information may be sought before personal data can be released. All requests should be made to info@abbotslangleyclinic.co.uk or by phoning 01923 268787 or writing to us at the address further below.13 Complaints In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by The Abbots Langley Clinic you have the right to complain to us. If you do not get a response within 30 days, you can complain to the ICO.The details for each of these contacts are:The Abbots Langley Clinic Nicola Buckwald, GDPR Coordinator
10 Abbots Rd, Abbots Langley WD5 0AZ. Telephone 01923 268787 Email: info@abbotslangleyclinic.co.ukICO Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF Telephone +44(0) 303 123 1113 Email: https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/
Cart
Item Removed. Undo
No products in the cart.
Checkout - £0.00
01
